Guide to the Trigant Burrow Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Attention; Camps -- New York (State); Conflict (Psychology); Consciousness; Families; Father and child; Group psychoanalysis; Humanistic psychology; Interpersonal relations; Physician and patient; Psychiatry; Psychoanalysis; Psychology; Psychophysiology; Psychotherapist and patient; Psychotherapy patients; Recreation; Social psychiatry; Social psychology; Lifwynn Camp (Merrill, N.Y.); Merrill (N.Y.) -- History; Monographs; Reprints; Psychiatrists; Psychoanalysts; Anderson, Sherwood, 1876-1941; Anspacher, Louis Kaufman, 1878-1947; Baetjer, Harry N.; Bellows, C. C.; Bentley, Alys E. (Alys Eliza), 1868-1951; Bispham, George Tucker, d. 1949; Blum, Bessie M., d. 1962; Bredow, Miriam, 1895-; Brill, A. A. (Abraham Arden), 1874-1948; Bruce, Rosalind, d. 1935; Burrow, Anastasia Devereux, 1838-1925; Burrow, Emily Sherwood Bryan, 1873-1951; Burrow, Geraldine Dickson, d. 1943; Burrow, Helen Stapleton, 1920-; Burrow, John Devereux, 1905-1948; Burrow, Trigant, 1875-1950; de Lorenzi, Sue; Deming, Eleanor, d. 1961; Dickson, Elizabeth; Dudley, Pendleton, 1876-1966; Dummer, Ethel Sturges; Edwards, C. Bryant; Eliot, Thomas D. (Thomas Dawes), 1889-1973; Ellis, Havelock, 1859-1939; Falk, Emil Albert; Federn, Paul; Freud, Sigmund, 1856-1939; Frost, Paul; Galt, Alfreda S.; Galt, Minnie E.; Galt, William Egleston, 1904-1955; Gans, Bird Stein, d. 1945; Guggenheimer, Aimée, 1876-1964; Guggenheimer, Flora A., 1872-1952; Guion, Connie, 1882-1971; Hayakawa, S. I. (Samuel Ichiyé), 1906-1992; Henderson, C. Hanford (Charles Hanford), 1861-1941; Hölljes, Nelly, d. 1946; Holtzman, Florence Lee; Howenstein, Karl, 1888-; Huiskamp, John E., 1874-1929; Jelliffe, Smith Ely, 1866-1945; Jung, C. G. (Carl Gustav), 1875-1961; Kinder, Elaine Flitner, 1890-1979; Kirby, Daniel Bartholemew, 1891-; Korzybski, Alfred, 1879-1950; La Garde, Richard D., 1884-1967; Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert), 1885-1930; Leigh, Helen L. Pease; Leigh, John Randolph, d. 1958; Lyman, David R. (David Russell), 1876-1956; MacCurdy, John T. (John Thompson), 1886-; Mayne, Robert; Merrill, Clare; Meyer, Adolf, 1866-1950; Moore, Mary Milligan, 1886-1977; Moore, Merrill, 1903-1957; Nash, Lucia Devereux Smith; Oberndorf, Clarence P. (Clarence Paul), 1882-1954; Ogden, C. K. (Charles Kay), 1889-1957; Parr, Grace Whitford, d. 1963; Pope, Laura Spencer Portor; Raven, Alice; Read, Herbert, 1893-1968; Reilly, Marjorie E. Young; Reymert, Martin L. (Martin Luther), 1883-1953; Rosenberg, Max; Rowland, John Howard; Shackleford, Elizabeth Burrow, 1910-; Shields, Clarence, 1885-1951; Sill, Alfreda Payson, 1885-1982; Smithwick, Fanita M., d. 1953; Spindle, Richard Buckner, 1886-1954; Stein, Leo, 1872-1947; Syz, Emily Sherwood Burrow, 1909-; Syz, Hans C.; Thayer, Ellen; Thompson, Charles Baker, 1888-; Thornton, Rosalie; Tomlinson, Albin A.; Twinem, Francis Patton, 1896-; Vaillant, René E. G. (René Eugene Gabriel), 1891-; Wallace, Kevin, (Ballroom dancer); Webster, Charles; Wechsler, E. Barbara; Wholey, Cornelius C.; Willcox, Louise Collier, 1865-1929; Wondolowski, Charles A.; Yerkes, Robert M. (Robert Mearns), 1876-1956; Burrows family; American Psychoanalytic Association; Lifwynn Foundation for Laboratory Research in Analytic and Social Psychiatry; Lifwynn Foundation
- Main Correspondence File, 1875-1983; Series I; 20.25' (49 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains forty-four boxes of alphabetically arranged correspondence files, one box of Trigant Burrow papers, and four boxes of notebooks of correspondence. Material is arranged in chronological order within each folder and individuals, organizations, journals, etc. are given separate listings, provided the file contains six or more items to, from, and about that person or organization. Letters of people who appear one to five times in the Trigant Burrow Papers are filed alphabetically with the first letter of the surname in "Letter" general files. Folders containing ten or more items to, from, and about a person or organization are marked with an asterisk(*).
  - The Trigant Burrow Papers: A User's Guide, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "A" general, 1919-1950, undated (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
  - Abel, Theodora, 1935-1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Abt, Lawrence E., 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ackley, Emileta W., 1931 (Box 46, Folder 1216)
  - Ackley, Henry B.(*), 1922-1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Additional correspondence, 1923 (Box 46, Folder 1216)
  - Adams, Mary B., 1919-1920, undated (Box 46, Folder 1217)
  - Adler, Herman M., 1926-1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Afnan, Soheil(*), 1926-1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Allee, W. C.(*), 1941-1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Allen, Mildred, 1928-1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Allen, Wray W., 1928-1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Allport, Floyd H., 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Allport, Gordon W., 1925-1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science(*), 1925-1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Ethnological Society, 1936-1950 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The American Foundation Studies in Government(*), 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Journal of Psychiatry (*), 1925-1938 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Journal of Pschology, 1942-1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - American Journal of Sociology (*), 1926-1946 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - American Sociological Society (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - American Medical Association(*), 1925-1949 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The American Mercury, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - American Neurological Association, 1924-1927 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - American Psychiatric Association(*), 1925-1950 (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
  - American Psychoanalytic Association(*), 1922-1932 (Box 1, Folder 24-26)
  - American Psychological Association(*), 1924-1950 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - American Psychopathological Association(*), 1912-1977 (Box 2, Folder 28-30)
  - American Sociological Review, 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - American Sociological Society, 1941-1950 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Amsden, George S.(*), 1925-1935 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Anderson, Daniel G.(*), 1923-1926 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Anderson, Sherwood(*), 1917-1949 (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
  - Anderson, Tennessee (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
  - Andrews, George Clinton(*), 1927-1949 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Anspacher, Louis K.(*), 1926-1947 (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
  - Antonio, Sister Mary(*), 1923-1927 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Archives of Neurology and Psychiatry (*), 1933-1943 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Archivio Generale, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Arduino, Grace C., 1943-1948 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Armstrong, Stuart(*), 1941-1946 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Arnold, Magda B., 1944-1949 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Atkinson, Arnalia J., 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Atlantic Monthly (*), 1924-1948 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - The Australian Psychology Centre Newsletter, 1947-1950 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - "B" general, 1908-1950, undated (Box 2, Folder 48-52)
  - Baetjer, Harry N.(*), 1926-1945 (Box 3, Folder 54-55)
    General
    See also: box 53, folder 1496-1500
    See also: box 56, folder 1558-1561
  - Bailey, David Alger(*), 1928-1944 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Bailey, Herbert S., Jr., 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Baker, George P., 1914 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Baker, H. G., 1947, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Baldwin, James Mark, 1926-1927 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Bally, Gustav, 1926-1927 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Banks, Kathleen Marie(*), 1941 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Bard, Philip, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Barker, Lewellys F., 1924-1938 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer(*), 1926-1949 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Baruch, Bernard M., 1945-1948 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Beardslee, Martin, 1930-1932 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Beaudry, Yvonne, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Beaver Camp, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Belcher, Anne M.(*), 1934-1949, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Bellows, C. C.
    See: box 59, folder 1656-1665
  - Benrimo, Katharine(*), undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Benson, Rita Romilly(*), 1920-1949 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Bentley, Alys E.(*), 1924-1949 (Box 3, Folder 70-71)
  - Bentley, Arthur F.(*), 1941-1950 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Bentley, Leta A.(*), 1922-1937 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Benton, William, 1949-1950 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Berens, Conrad, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Berger, Leon L.(*), 1941-1950 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Bergmann, Hugo(*), 1928-1935 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Bernays, Edward L., 1941-1946 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Bibb, Frank, 1926-1927 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Biographical Encyclopedia of the World, 1939-1946 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Biological Abstracts, 1935-1949 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - The Biology of Human Conflict (*), 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 81-83)
    See also: box 65, folder 1851
    See also: box 76, folder 2016-2076
    See also: box 95, folder 2438-2440
  - Birge, Jane Burges Sill, 1932-1948 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Bispham, George Tucker(*), 1923-1949 (Box 4, Folder 85-89)
  - Bispham, Helen R. S.(*) (Box 4, Folder 85-89)
  - Blum, Bessie M.(*), 1922-1948 (Box 4, Folder 90-94)
    See also: box 51, folder 1439-1444
  - Boas, George(*), 1925-1949 (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Bomberger, Christian Martin, 1923-1935 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Boni & Liveright, 1924-1926 (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Boyd Printing Co.(*), 1924-1927 (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Boyle, Terence J.(*), 1936-1949 (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Brady, Thomas, Jr., 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Bredow, Miriam M.
    See: box 44, folder 1172-1173
  - Brill, Abraham Arden(*), 1919-1948, undated (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - The British Journal of Medical Psychology (*), 1925-1933 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Brown, George Dobbin, 1922, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Brown, Thomas R., 1928 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Bruce, Elizabeth B. C.(*), 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Bruce, Rosalind(*), 1918-1933 (Box 4, Folder 105-107)
    See also: box 51, folder 1445
  - Bruce, Rosalind estate, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 108)
  - The Bruce Publishing Company, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 109)
  - Bryan family(*), 1904-1948 (Box 5, Folder 110-111)
  - Burke's Landed Gentry (*), 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 112)
  - Burlingame, C. C., 1946-1949 (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - Burnham, Susan Putnam(*), 1928-1936 (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - Burrow, Alan G.(*), 1926-1948 (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - Burrow, Anastasia Devereux(*), 1875-1925, undated (Box 5, Folder 116-120)
    See also: box 53, folder 1502-1503
  - Burrow, Clara(*), 1942-1946 (Box 5, Folder 121)
  - Burrow, Devereux
    See: box 9, folder 221
  - Burrow, Elizabeth
    See: box 32, folder 849-854
  - Burrow, Emily Sherwood
    See: box 35, folder 928-940
  - Burrow, Emily Sherwood Bryan(*), 1922-1930 May (Box 5, Folder 122-130)
    See also: box 51, folder 1446-1449
    See also: box 56, folder 1565-1573
  - Burrow, Emily Sherwood Bryan, 1930 June-1941 (Box 6, Folder 131-149)
  - Burrow, Emily Sherwood Bryan, 1942-1950 (Box 7, Folder 150-159)
  - Burrow, Geraldine Dickson(*), 1926-1942 (Box 7, Folder 160-161)
    See also: box 53, folder 1504-1505
  - Burrow, Helen Stapleton(*), 1939-1950 (Box 7, Folder 162-166)
  - Burrow, Inez, 1887 (Box 7, Folder 167)
  - Burrow, Inez(*), 1921-1931 (Box 7, Folder 168-170)
  - Burrow, John Devereux(*), 1909-1920 (Box 7, Folder 171)
    See also: box 51, folder 1450-1451
    See also: box 56, folder 1574-1577
  - Burrow, John Devereux, 1921-1947 (Box 8, Folder 172-191)
  - Burrow, John Devereux, 1948, undated (Box 9, Folder 192)
  - Burrow, J. R., 1938 (Box 9, Folder 193)
  - Burrow, Laura McClung
    See: box 23, folder 585
  - Burrow, Mary Cuthbert
    See: box 14, folder 341
  - Burrow, Mary Bragg, 1924-1930 (Box 9, Folder 194)
  - Burrow, Penelope Sherwood, 1943-1948 (Box 9, Folder 195)
  - Burrow, Trigant, 1909-1938, undated (Box 9, Folder 196)
    See also: box 61, folder 1720-1755
  - Burrow, Trigant: excerpts from letters(*), 1937-1940 (Box 9, Folder 197)
  - Burrow, Virginia, 1924, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 198)
  - Bush, Vannevar, 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 199)
  - "C" general, 1919-1950, undated (Box 9, Folder 200-204)
  - Callahan, William R., 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 205)
  - Campbell, Elizabeth(*), 1925-1938 (Box 9, Folder 206)
  - Cannon, Walter B.(*), 1927-1928 (Box 9, Folder 207)
  - Carlson, Anton J.(*), 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 208)
  - The Century Company, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 209)
  - Chapin, Mary K.(*), 1928, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 210)
  - Child Study Association of America(*), 1926-1945 (Box 9, Folder 211)
  - Clark, George Edward(*), 1922-1935 (Box 9, Folder 212)
  - Clark, L. Pierce(*), 1922-1933 (Box 9, Folder 213-215)
  - Coghill, George E.(*), 1932-1941 (Box 9, Folder 216)
  - Coghlan, Ralph, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 217)
  - Colson, Chester(*), 1941-1946 (Box 9, Folder 218)
  - Connecticut Medical License(*), 1927, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 219)
  - Connecticut State Department of Health, 1945-1950 (Box 9, Folder 220)
  - Connecticut State Medical Society, 1943-1950 (Box 9, Folder 220)
  - Conway, Devereux Burrow(*), 1933-1950 (Box 9, Folder 221)
  - Cope, Ellen(*), 1939, 1941, undated (Box 9, Folder 222)
  - Coriat, Etta, 1924-1925 (Box 10, Folder 223)
  - Coriat, Isador H.(*), 1922-1926 (Box 10, Folder 223)
  - Corning, H. K., 1941-1949 (Box 10, Folder 224)
  - Cory, Herbert F., 1921-1948 (Box 10, Folder 225)
  - Crampton, Savington W., 1921 (Box 10, Folder 226)
  - Cripps, Sir Stafford, 1948-1949 (Box 10, Folder 226)
  - Cronbach, Abraham, 1926-1932 (Box 10, Folder 227)
  - Crown Publishers(*), 1948-1950 (Box 10, Folder 228)
  - "D" general, 1897-1950 (Box 10, Folder 229-232)
  - Davis, Hallowell, 1937, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 233)
  - Delgado, Honorio F., 1948-1949 (Box 10, Folder 234)
  - de Lorenzi, Sue(*), 1922-1949 (Box 10, Folder 235-238)
  - Deming, Agathe(*), 1923-1927, undated (Box 10, Folder 239)
  - Deming, Eleanor(*), 1921-1949 (Box 10, Folder 240-241)
  - Devereux, Antonia
    See: box 2, folder 39
  - Devereux, George, 1939, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 242)
  - Dew, Albert G., 1928-1936 (Box 10, Folder 243)
  - Dewey, John(*), 1926-1970 (Box 10, Folder 244)
  - Dick, William M.(*), 1944-1949 (Box 10, Folder 245)
  - Dickson, Elizabeth(*), 1925-1950 (Box 10, Folder 246-248)
  - Dickson, Geraldine
    See: box 53, folder 1504-1505
  - Dickson R. Hunter, 1927-1945 (Box 10, Folder 249)
  - Dickson, Sadie, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 249)
  - Diggins, Elmer, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 250)
  - Dinsmore, Emma A.(*), 1922-1924, undated (Box 10, Folder 251)
  - Dodd, Mead & Company, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 252)
  - Doing, Ruth, 1924-1949 (Box 11, Folder 253)
  - Doran, George H. Company, 1922-1926 (Box 11, Folder 254)
  - Dudley, Pendleton(*), 1923-1950 (Box 11, Folder 255-259)
  - Dummer, Ethel Sturges(*), 1925-1954 (Box 11, Folder 260-262)
  - Dunlap, Knight(*), 1918-1949 (Box 11, Folder 263)
  - "E" general, 1923-1950 (Box 11, Folder 264-265)
  - Earle, Dorothy, 1925-1926 (Box 11, Folder 266)
  - Eastman, Max, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 266)
  - Edwards, C. Bryant(*), 1924-1937 (Box 11, Folder 267)
    See also: box 51, folder 1452-1453
  - Egleston, G. P.(*), 1923-1927 (Box 11, Folder 268)
  - Egleston, William, 1923-1924 (Box 11, Folder 269)
  - Ehrlich, Moses L.(*), 1932-1950 (Box 11, Folder 270)
  - Eliasberg, Wladimir, 1929-1944 (Box 11, Folder 271)
  - Eliot, Thomas D.(*), 1927-1949 (Box 11, Folder 272-274)
  - Ellis, Havelock(*), 1927-1938 (Box 11, Folder 275)
  - Emerson, Alfred E.(*), 1942-1949 (Box 11, Folder 276)
  - The Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 277)
  - Encyclopedia of Psychology, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 277)
  - Engel, Anna, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 278)
  - Engel, Katie L.(*), 1923-1925 (Box 11, Folder 278)
  - Ensworth, Herbert K.(*), 1941-1942 (Box 11, Folder 279)
  - Etc: A Review of General Semantics (*), 1943, 1946, undated (Box 11, Folder 280)
  - Evans, Elida(*), 1926-1928 (Box 11, Folder 281)
  - "F" general, 1919-1950 (Box 12, Folder 282-284)
  - Fairfield County Medical Association(*), 1945-1950 (Box 12, Folder 285)
  - Falk, Emil Albert(*), 1934-1950 (Box 12, Folder 286-287)
  - Federn, Paul(*), 1925-1928 (Box 12, Folder 288)
  - Flanagan, Edward J., 1945-1951 (Box 12, Folder 289)
  - Fleming, Elizabeth B., 1921, 1925, undated (Box 12, Folder 289)
  - Foldes, Lili Rendy(*), 1941-1942 (Box 12, Folder 290)
  - Fordham University(*), 1935-1950 (Box 12, Folder 291)
  - The Forum, 1924-1932 (Box 12, Folder 292)
  - Foster, Thomas G., 1945-1949 (Box 12, Folder 293)
  - Fournet, Sybil, 1944-1950 (Box 12, Folder 293)
  - Fox, Charles B., 1945-1948 (Box 12, Folder 294)
  - Frank, Lawrence K.(*), 1933-1939 (Box 12, Folder 295)
  - Frank, Waldo, 1928 (Box 12, Folder 296)
  - Frank, Alma M., 1938-1941 (Box 12, Folder 296)
  - Frazier, Jeannette, 1932-1933 (Box 12, Folder 297)
  - Freeman, Mary(*), 1925-1948 (Box 12, Folder 298)
  - Freud, Sigmund(*), 1913-1935 (Box 12, Folder 299)
  - Fritchey, Ethel M., 1927 (Box 12, Folder 300)
  - Frost, Paul(*), 1918-1950 (Box 12, Folder 301-304)
  - Fulton, John F.(*), 1939-1949 (Box 12, Folder 305)
  - "G" general, 1921-1950 (Box 12, Folder 306-308)
  - Galt, Alfreda Sill(*), 1935-1950 (Box 13, Folder 309-313)
  - Galt, Minnie E.(*), 1922-1950 (Box 13, Folder 314-319)
  - Galt, William C.(*), 1922-1937 (Box 13, Folder 320)
  - Galt, William Egleston(*), 1922-1939 (Box 13, Folder 321-329)
    See also: box 51, folder 1454
  - Galt, William Egleston, 1940-1949, undated (Box 14, Folder 330-335)
  - Gans, Bird Stein(*), 1925-1943 (Box 14, Folder 336-337)
  - Gans, Howard S., 1945 (Box 14, Folder 338)
  - Gans, Robert S., 1945 (Box 14, Folder 338)
  - Gantt, W. Horsley, 1934-1948 (Box 14, Folder 339)
  - Gardner, Gail(*), 1921-1943 (Box 14, Folder 340)
  - Garrett, Mary Cuthbert Burrow(*), 1925-1949 (Box 14, Folder 341)
  - Gaul, Cecilia(*), 1924-1926 (Box 14, Folder 342)
  - Gerard, R. W.(*), 1939-1949 (Box 14, Folder 343)
  - Gesell, Arnold(*), 1935-1949 (Box 14, Folder 344)
  - Giddings, Franklin H.(*), 1925-1928 (Box 14, Folder 345)
  - Goldstein, Kurt(*), 1935-1950 (Box 14, Folder 346)
  - Gottlieb, Charles(*), 1941-1950 (Box 14, Folder 347)
  - Graves, Charles C.(*), 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 348)
  - Graves, Leonard M.(*), 1918-1928 (Box 14, Folder 349)
  - Gregg, Alan, 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 350)
  - Gruenberg, Sidonie M., 1927-1936 (Box 14, Folder 351)
  - Guggenheimer, Aimée, 1922-1936 January (Box 14, Folder 352-361)
    See also: box 51, folder 1455-1457
  - Vaillant, René(*), 1936 February -1950 (Box 15, Folder 362-376)
  - Guggenheimer, Flora A.(*), 1921-1939 (Box 15, Folder 377-383)
    See also: box 51, folder 1458
  - Guggenheimer, Flora A., 1940-1950 (Box 16, Folder 384-387)
  - Guion, Connie M.(*), 1936-1950 (Box 16, Folder 388-389)
  - Gutkind, Erich, 1935-1939 (Box 16, Folder 390)
  - "H" general, 1925-1950, undated (Box 16, Folder 391-396)
  - Hackett, Charlotte C., 1939-1948 (Box 16, Folder 397)
  - Hackfield, A. W., 1935-1936 (Box 16, Folder 397)
  - Hader, John J., 1928-1935 (Box 16, Folder 398)
  - Haes, E. O.(*), 1948-1950 (Box 16, Folder 399)
  - Haldane, J. B. S., 1925-1949 (Box 16, Folder 400)
  - Hamman, Louis(*), 1921-1945, undated (Box 16, Folder 401)
  - Hancock, Frank(*), 1923-1934 (Box 16, Folder 402)
  - Harcourt, Brace and Company, Inc.(*), 1925-1949 July (Box 16, Folder 403-408)
  - Harcourt, Brace and Company, Inc., 1949 August-1950 (Box 17, Folder 409-411)
  - Harding, T. Swann(*), 1946-1948 (Box 17, Folder 412)
  - Harper & Brothers(*), 1924-1948 (Box 17, Folder 413)
  - Harper's Magazine (Box 17, Folder 413)
  - Harrington, Helen(*), 1930-1935 (Box 17, Folder 414)
  - Hauser, Louis A., 1940-1941 (Box 17, Folder 415)
  - Haviland, C. Floyd(*), 1925-1930 (Box 17, Folder 416)
  - Hayakawa, S. I.(*), 1946-1950 (Box 17, Folder 417)
    See also: box 11, folder 280
  - The Heckscher Institute for Child Health, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 418)
  - Henderson, C. Hanford(*), 1920-1940 (Box 17, Folder 419-424)
  - Henline, Roy B.(*), 1943-1945 (Box 17, Folder 425)
  - Herrick, C. Judson(*), 1935-1950 (Box 17, Folder 426)
  - Herskovits, Melville J., 1946-1949 (Box 17, Folder 427)
  - Higgins, Louis Severance, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 428)
  - Hightower, Elizabeth Scheetz(*), 1925-1939 (Box 17, Folder 429)
  - Hightower, Felda, 1936-1940 (Box 17, Folder 430)
  - Hinsie, Leland E.(*), 1939-1949 (Box 17, Folder 431-432)
  - Hipsley, Roland W., 1940-1949 (Box 17, Folder 433)
  - Hitchcock, H. Wiley, 1946, undated (Box 17, Folder 433)
  - Hoagland, Hudson, 1944-1949 (Box 17, Folder 434)
  - Hölljes, Mary E., 1946-1949 (Box 17, Folder 435)
  - Hölljes, Nelly(*), 1921-1944 (Box 17, Folder 436-439)
    See also: box 52, folder 1459-1462
  - Holsopple, James Quinter(*), 1926-1938 (Box 17, Folder 439)
  - Holtzman, Florence Lee(*), 1923-1949 (Box 18, Folder 440-441)
  - House, S. Daniel(*), 1928 (Box 18, Folder 442)
  - Howe, Irving, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 443)
  - Howenstein, Edith, 1931-1932 (Box 18, Folder 444)
  - Howenstein, Karl(*), 1928-1950 (Box 18, Folder 445-453)
  - Hoy, Ralph L.(*), 1936-1948 (Box 18, Folder 454)
  - Hubbell, Frances(*), 1949-1950 (Box 18, Folder 455)
  - Huebsch, B. W., 1921-1925 (Box 18, Folder 456)
  - Huiskamp, John E.(*), 1924-1929 (Box 18, Folder 457)
    See also: box 52, folder 1463-1468
  - Huiskamp, John E. estate, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 458)
  - Hull, Otis, 1944-1949 (Box 18, Folder 459)
  - Human Biology (*), 1933-1941 (Box 18, Folder 460)
  - Human Genetics Society of America, 1948-1950 (Box 18, Folder 461)
  - Humphreys, Edward J.(*), 1935-1939 (Box 18, Folder 462)
  - Hunt, Elizabeth Hadley, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 463)
  - Hurd, Lee M.(*), 1930-1943 (Box 18, Folder 464)
  - Huxley, Julian S., 1926-1935 (Box 18, Folder 465)
  - "I" general, 1920-1950 (Box 18, Folder 466)
  - Imandt, Robert, 1924-1925 (Box 18, Folder 467)
  - Important letters, 1926-1933 (Box 18, Folder 468)
  - Institute of General Semantics, 1948-1949 (Box 19, Folder 469)
  - International Congress of Philosophy(*), 1926, 1930 (Box 19, Folder 470)
  - International Congress of Psychology, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 471)
  - International Journal of Psycho-Analysis (*), 1925-1927 (Box 19, Folder 472)
  - International Psycho-Analytical Association(*), 1925-1926 (Box 19, Folder 473)
  - Internationale Zeitschrift für Psychoanalyse (*), 1913-1928 (Box 19, Folder 474)
  - Isham, Mary Keyt, 1925-1928 (Box 19, Folder 475)
  - "J" general, 1924-1950 (Box 19, Folder 476-477)
  - Jastrow, Joseph(*), 1924-1938 (Box 19, Folder 478)
  - Jelliffe, Samuel Ely(*), 1924-1938 (Box 19, Folder 479)
  - Jenison, Madge(*), 1920-1948 (Box 19, Folder 480)
  - The Jewish National and University Library, 1949-1950 (Box 19, Folder 481)
  - Jobson, Marian, 1948-1949 (Box 19, Folder 482)
  - Johns Hopkins University(*), 1923-1949, undated (Box 19, Folder 483)
  - Johns Hopkins Alumni Association, 1941-1950 (Box 19, Folder 484)
  - Johns Hopkins Alumni Fund, 1947-1949, undated (Box 19, Folder 484)
  - Johnson, Alice E., 1926-1928 (Box 19, Folder 485)
  - Johnson, Buford, 1931, 1935 (Box 19, Folder 485)
  - Jones, William B., 1923 (Box 19, Folder 486)
  - Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology (*), 1924-1949 (Box 19, Folder 487)
  - Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology (*), 1932-1934 (Box 19, Folder 488)
  - Journal of Nervous and Mental Diseases (*), 1926-1945 (Box 19, Folder 489)
  - Journal of Psychology (*), 1935-1942 (Box 19, Folder 490)
  - Journal of Social Philosophy (*), 1936-1939 (Box 19, Folder 491)
  - Journal of Social Psychology (*), 1928-1942 (Box 19, Folder 492)
  - The Journal of the American Medical Association (*), 1924-1941 (Box 19, Folder 493)
  - Jung, Carl G., 1911-1937 (Box 19, Folder 494)
    See also: box 3, folder 82
  - "K" general, 1920-1955, undated (Box 19, Folder 495-498)
  - Katz, David, 1948-1949 (Box 20, Folder 499)
  - Katz, J. R., 1920-1933, undated (Box 20, Folder 500)
  - Kegan, Paul, Trench, Trubner & Co., Ltd.(*), 1927-1947 (Box 20, Folder 501)
    See also: box 28, folder 730-733
    See also: box 30, folder 792-795
    See also: box 31, folder 813-814